# LAKMAL PADMAKUMARA

### Software Engineer | Product Manager | Agile Consultant

Goethestr 36, Erlangen, 91054, Germany

+16782943957 rclakmal@gmail.com

## **PROFILE**

Over 6 years of experience working with agile teams, building digital products & services in multiple domains, playing roles of a software engineer, a product owner, a scrum master and an agile coach across Asia, Europe, and North America. Experienced and curious about UX/CX best practices, Lean/Agile working modes, and Customer Co-Creation

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

❖ Agile Consultant, Siemens AG	=
	Atlanta, USA
• Co-facilitate agile training workshops for internal Siemens R&D teams and external clients to enable	
organizational adaption of agile methodologies. (Scrum, SAFe)	
• Act as the scrum master during the initial stages of adaption and train successors from within the teams	
❖ Product Management, Siemens AG	May 2018 — Sep 2019
	gapore/ Shanghai, China
<ul> <li>Managed the delivery of key UX improvements to MindSphere (Siemens IIoT cloud platform) including</li> </ul>	Supere, emangina, emina
better error handling, in-app notifications and service status page	
• Founded <b>global CX team</b> for with 4 other PM colleagues to establish user-centric product development	
practices across all R&D teams (e.g. Personas, Storyboarding & User story mapping)	
• Acted as the <b>onsite CX expert</b> during the product launch in China by facilitating design discussions and	
conducting <b>user interviews</b> to identify required regional product differences	
Working Environment: Jira, Confluence, Balsamiq, SAFe	
Software Engineer (part time), Multiple Employers	Nov 2015 — Mar 2018
	Munich, Germany
<ul> <li>Netlight Consulting Gmbh, Jan 2018 - Mar 2018 (Technologies: Java, Selenium, Gitlab CI/CD)</li> </ul>	
• Siemens AG, Cooperate Technology, Mar 2017 - Dec 2017 (Technologies: Sencha Ext JS, Selenium)	
<ul> <li>Airbus Defense and Space Gmbh, Sep 2016 - Feb 2017 (Technologies: Python, R)</li> </ul>	
• Cliqz Gmbh, Nov 2015 - Feb 2016 (Technologies: Python, AWS S3/EMR, Gitlab)	
Software Engineer/ Took Load Winters Com	E 1 001/ 0 0015
❖ Software Engineer/ Tech Lead, Virtusa Corp	
• Joined the British Telecom offshore development team as a full-stack engineer, and within a year promoted	Colombo, Sri Lanka
as a tech lead for a team of 6 developers.	
*	
• Led the development team to <b>establish Scrum</b> within the project team with required coaching.	
• Recipient of the "Personal Excellence Award - 2015" for the outstanding contributions to the project by	
British Telecom CIO	
<ul> <li>Working Environment: J2EE, Spring, JavaScript, Oracle, WebLogic, Riverbed Traffic Manager, Scrum</li> </ul>	

### **EDUCATION**

<b>♦</b> Technical University of Munich  MS Computer Science	· Oct 2015 — Dec 2017 Munich, Germany
Thesis: A data-driven model to predict UX through user activity tracking. (grade 1.0, the best score in German scale)	
❖ University of Moratuwa  BS Computer Science	<ul> <li>Jun 2008 — Apr 2013</li> <li>Colombo, Sri Lanka</li> </ul>

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

# Remote Selected to contribute to TEAMMATES, open-source peer evaluation tool, as a summer intern out of 100+ applications. Developed advanced reporting and visualization features, which improved the overall productivity and user experience of evaluators. • Working Environment: Java, JavaScript, Selenium, GitHub Full-Stack Engineer, Comerge AG Feb 2013 — Feb 2014 Zurich, Switzerland · Developed multiple new features to the web portal of mobility.ch (one of the leading car-sharing portals in Europe) including an interactive map to show available vehicles and its locations. Developed an automated test suite for major user journeys using Selenium, which improved the productivity of the releases by over 10% Working Environment: GWT, Java, JavaScript, Selenium, JUnit, Maven, Git, SVN, Jenkins, Jira, and Scrum ❖ Software Engineer, Audials AG ...... Feb 2011 — Sep 2011 Karlsruhe, Germany · Developed content-based filtering algorithms to identify irrelevant & false information of Audials online streaming logs, which improved the creation time of Audials' database (by over 5%) & quality of Audials' artists/music recommendations (by over 25% based on usage data) Working Environment: Python, PHP, MySQL, Mantis, CruiseControl.net, SVN, and Scrum EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES Trondheim, Norway International Student Festival in Trondheim (ISFiT) · Represented Sri Lanka & University of Moratuwa in ISFiT 2013, the biggest student festival in the world, where the focus topic was 'the role of youth in conflict resolution and global development' Colombo, Sri Lanka World Conference on Youth Facilitated a group of 50+ local & international delegates on the topic of systematic inequalities at World Conference on Youth 2014. Conducted sessions, workshops and dialogues on 3 consecutive days and moderated panel discussions on the same & related topics with local/foreign ministers, parliamentarians, youth activists and UN representatives Colombo, Sri Lanka IAESTE, Sri Lanka · Served as the Local Committee President for Sri Lankan chapter of IAESTE (The International Association for the Exchange of Students for Technical Experience) · Led a team of 20 local students in facilitating the arrival and the stay in Sri Lanka for interns from countries like India, Germany, Switzerland, Norway, Japan, Australia, Austria, UK. • Led the Sri Lankan team to win the "Best IAESTE day" award surpassing 88 countries in 2012. **CERTIFICATIONS** ❖ Certified Scrum Master (CSM) Feb 2014 — Present REFERENCES

References available upon request .....